hey guys this looks like a fun one we're
trying to find the ratio of the pink
area to the green area let's do this so
first let's try to find the area of
these yin-yang things so let's pull them
out and if we put them together they
should make a circle so it just be half
of that Circle and they don't these make
an ellipse all right scrap that idea
let's try something else so let's draw
the radius right here in fact let's draw
all these radiuses so that we have a
square in the middle right here and
let's focus on that square each of these
sides are two radiuses so we can call it
2 R and yes radiuses is the plural of
radius we could also say radi so the
area of the square is going to be 2 R *
2 R that's the same thing as 4 R 2 let's
look at another copy of the square down
here let's pull apart these quarter
circles bring down this green part let's
rotate all these quarter circles to make
a circle the area of this circle will be
P pi r s the area of the green stuff is
then going to be the area of this Square
minus the area of this circle now we
don't need this circle anymore so we can
get rid of that let's bring this up here
and this is important so let's put a box
around it let's go back up to this
square up here let's cut the square in
half and let's find the length of this
diagonal well this ends up making a 4545
0 triangle so it ends up being < TK of 2
* one of these sides so the diagonal is
equal to 2 R < TK of2 if you don't know
about the 454590 shortcut here's the
Pythagorean theorem right here pause it
if you want to check it let's clean all
this stuff up and put a box around this
now let's find the area of our large
Circle so we know that the diagonal the
square is equal to 2 < tk2 R and now we
don't need the square anymore and then
this right here is a radius and this
right here is a radius the diameter will
be equal to two of the radiuses plus 2 >
2 R and if we want to know what the
radius of the largest circle is we would
just divide all that stuff by 2 which
gives us r + < tk2 r and now to find the
area of this circle we're going to do PI
radius squ where this right here is the
radius and then a binomial squared ends
up being the binomial times itself so we
can foil this out we'll leave the pi out
front and then R * R is R 2 R * < tk2 R
is < tk2 R 2 < tk2 R * R is < tk2 R 2
and < tk2 R * < tk2 R is = to 2 R 2 and
then we can clean this up R 2 + 2 R 2 is
3 R 2 and right here we have 2 < tk2 R 2
so that would be 2 < tk2 R 2 and then we
can distribute the pi so we now have the
area of this large Circle and we can put
a box around that we're trying to find
the pink area divided by the green area
I think that is what this says so the
pink area is going to be this whole
circle minus this green stuff and then
the green area is going to be this green
stuff we can get rid of these
parentheses and distribute the negative
all six of these terms has an R squ so
we can factor out the r squ and then we
can cancel those R SS and then on top
this 3 pi and this 1 Pi can become 4 pi
and now we are done this is the exact
value of the answer and end up being
approximately
20308 how exciting